A Finding Aid to the Leo Castelli Gallery Records, circa 1880-2000, bulk 1957-1999, in the Archives of American Art AAA.leocast
Archives of American Art
- Sound and Video Recordings, circa 1950s-2000; Series 11; (Boxes 181-190, 232; 10.3 linear feet)
  - Video Recordings, 1969-2000; 11.2
    - Castelli, Leo - Episode 3 (Master Copy), circa 1980s-1990s; (1 VHS tape) (Box 182, Folder 6)
    - Castelli Graphics - "Jackson Pollock,", 1981; (3 folders; 3 ¾ U-Matic tapes) (Box 182, Folder 7-9)
    - Castelli Graphics - "Jackson Pollock,", 1981; (1 ¾ U-Matic tape) (Box 183, Folder 1)
    - "Castelli's Spaziergang,", circa 1980s-1990s; (1 VHS tape) (Box 183, Folder 2)
    - Cettina-Umago, circa 1980s-1990s; (1 VHS tape) (Box 183, Folder 3)
    - Collins, Hannah - LA Cantant, circa 1980s-1990s; (1 VHS tape) (Box 183, Folder 4)
    - "Cue" Interview with M. McKay (Nov. 22), 1977; (1 ¾ U-Matic tape) (Box 183, Folder 5)
    - Darboven, Hanne - Leo Castelli Interview from PAL VHS German Television, circa 1980s-1990s; (2 folders; 1 ¾ U-Matic tape and 1 VHS tape) (Box 183, Folder 6-7)
    - "Edward Ruscha with Nancy Reese," BBC Program, 1978; (1 ¾ U-Matic tape) (Box 183, Folder 8)
    - Flavin, Dan - "In Daylight and Cool White," by Charles Ruas, 1979; (1 ¾ U-Matic tape) (Box 184, Folder 1)
    - Flavin, Dan - "In Daylight and Cool White," by Charles Ruas and Marnie Mueller, circa 1980; (1 ¾ U-Matic tape) (Box 184, Folder 2)
    - "Genesis-Earthflowers-Humanity" Series Sample, by John Sirila, circa 1980s-1990s; (1 VHS tape) (Box 184, Folder 3)
    - Grisi, Laura - "Misura del Tempo,", 1969; (1 ¾ U-Matic tape) (Box 184, Folder 4)
    - "Il Signore Dell'Arte: Leo Castelli" by Raffaello Siniscalco (English version), 1994; (1 VHS tape) (Box 184, Folder 5)
    - "Il Signore Dell'Arte: Leo Castelli" di Raffaello Siniscalco (Italian version), 1994; (1 VHS tape) (Box 184, Folder 6)
    - "An Interview with Leo Castelli" - WNET/Cable Arts, circa late 1970s; (2 folders; 1 ¾ U-Matic tape and 1 VHS tape) (Box 184, Folder 7-8)
    - "It's Blowing Up in My Hands" (Thru 1st), circa 1970s-1990s; (1 ¾ U-Matic tape) (Box 184, Folder 9)
    - "It's Blowing Up in My Hands" (Thru Fwd. R-3), circa 1970s-1990s; (1 ¾ U-Matic tape) (Box 185, Folder 1)
    - Johns, Jasper - "Take an Object," Namuth/Wechsler Productions, 1990; (1 VHS tape) (Box 185, Folder 2)
    - Koons, Jeff - "South Bank Show," Anthony d'Offay Gallery, 1993; (1 VHS tape) (Box 185, Folder 3)
    - "Large Scale Projects Claes Oldenburg/Coosje van Bruggen" by Lana Pih Jokel and Nick Doob, 1991; (1 VHS tape) (Box 185, Folder 4)
    - "Leo Castelli" - A Work in Progress by Mame Kennedy, 1988, April 19; (2 folders; 1 ¾ U-Matic tape and 1 VHS tape) (Box 185, Folder 5-6)
    - Leo Castelli Gallery - 7 Days Promo, 1989, May; (1 VHS tape) (Box 185, Folder 7)
    - Leo Castelli Gallery - CNN, circa 1998; (2 VHS tapes) (Box 185, Folder 8)
    - Leo Castelli Talks with Art People in Mexico City ("WorldNet"), 1987, May 28; (2 folders; 1 ¾ U-Matic tape and 1 VHS tape; in English and Spanish) (Box 186, Folder 1-2)
    - Leo Castelli WorldNet 418/Arnet 118 (English), 1987, May 28; (1 VHS tape) (Box 186, Folder 3)
    - Leo Castelli XXXth Anniversary 1957-1987 (PAL/European System), circa 1987; (1 ¾ U-Matic tape) (Box 186, Folder 4)
    - Les Moyens de L'Urgence de Frauers [?] Grosjean, circa 1980s-1990s; (1 VHS tape) (Box 186, Folder 5)
    - Lichtenstein, Roy - Interview by BBC, 1979; (1 LVC60 tape) (Box 186, Folder 6)
    - Lichtenstein, Roy - "Reflections,", 1993; (1 VHS tape) (Box 186, Folder 7)
    - "made in U.S.A." by Markus Zöllner, 1993; (1 VHS tape) (Box 186, Folder 8)
    - "Making of an Artist" (German Television), circa 1970s-1980s; (1 ¾ U-Matic tape) (Box 186, Folder 9)
    - Merce Cunningham Dance Company - "Changing Steps,", 1989; (1 VHS tape) (Box 187, Folder 1)
    - "Merce Cunningham Studio,", circa 1970s-1980s; (1 ¾ U-Matic tape) (Box 187, Folder 2)
    - "Merce Cunningham Visits Leo Castelli" by Nam June Paik, rough footage, circa 1980s-1990s; (2 folders; 1 ¾ U-Matic tape and 1 VHS tape) (Box 187, Folder 3-4)
    - "Message to Leo - A Racers Project" - Sal Scarpitta Productions, 1986; (1 ¾ U-Matic tape) (Box 187, Folder 5)
    - "The National Gallery Celebrates" - 50th Anniversary Celebration, 1991; (1 VHS tape) (Box 187, Folder 6)
    - Nauman, Bruce - "Good Boy, Bad Boy,", circa 1970s; (1 ¾ U-Matic tape) (Box 187, Folder 7)
    - Nauman, Bruce - "World Peace," "Brooks Lips,", circa 1980s-1990s; (2 VHS tapes) (Box 187, Folder 8)
    - Oldenburg, Claes - Interview at Walker Arts Center, circa 1970s-1980s; (1 ¾ U-Matic tape) (Box 188, Folder 1)
    - Oldenburg, Claes - Interview by Martin Friedman, 1975, April 4; (1 ¾ U-Matic tape) (Box 188, Folder 2)
    - Plaisance "60 Secondes..." - Leo Castelli, circa 1980s-1990s; (1 VHS tape) (Box 188, Folder 3)
    - Rabinovich, Bill - "ArtSeen," NYC Tribute to Leo Castelli, 2000; (1 VHS tape) (Box 188, Folder 4)
    - Rauschenberg, Robert - Interview, Part I (Colorado State University), 1982; (1 ¾ U-Matic tape) (Box 188, Folder 5)
    - Rauschenberg, Robert - Interview, Part II (Colorado State University), 1982; (1 ¾ U-Matic tape) (Box 188, Folder 6)
    - Rauschenberg, Robert - "Man At Work," BBC Television, 1997; (1 VHS tape) (Box 188, Folder 7)
    - Rosenquist, James - A Film by Erwin Lester (Signed), 1998; (1 VHS tape) (Box 188, Folder 8)
    - Rosenquist, James - "Welcome to the Water Planet,", 1990; (1 VHS tape) (Box 188, Folder 9)
    - "Scanning New York Art,", 1995, February-March; (1 VHS tape) (Box 189, Folder 1)
    - Scarpitta, Sal and Joan Bankemper - "Potato Masher,", 1985; (1 ¾ U-Matic tape) (Box 189, Folder 2)
    - Star Thief (Little Leo) - Mike Huber Clinic/Pat Donohue Up, 1995, January; (1 VHS tape) (Box 189, Folder 3)
    - Starn, Doug and Mike - "Gravity of Light," "Behind My Eye," "Nowhere to Land"; Documentation by Leo Castelli Gallery, 1998; (2 folders; 1 ¾ U-Matic tape and 2 VHS tapes) (Box 189, Folder 4-5)
    - Starn, Doug and Mike - "Sphere of Influence,", circa 1990s; (1 VHS tape) (Box 189, Folder 6)
    - Teshigahara, Iemoto Hiroshi [in Japanese?], 1990, June 2; (1 VHS tape) (Box 189, Folder 7)
    - Therrien, Robert - Interview, Carnegie International, 1995; (1 VHS tape) (Box 189, Folder 8)
    - "Today in New York" with Leo Castelli, Rodney Greenblatt, and Anina Nosei, 1985, April 30; (1 ¾ U-Matic tape) (Box 189, Folder 9)
    - "Today in New York" with Leo Castelli, Rodney Greenblatt, and Anina Nosei, 1985, April 30; (1 VHS tape) (Box 190, Folder 1)
    - Unidentified Beta Tape, circa 1970s-1990s; (1 Beta tape) (Box 190, Folder 2)
    - Unidentified Endless Loop Video Cartridge, circa 1970s-1980s; (1 ½ reel) (Box 190, Folder 3)
    - Unidentified U-Matic Tape (#12 Lost; #4), 1984; (1 ¾ U-Matic tape) (Box 190, Folder 4)
    - "Vu D'Afrique", Salto Productions, circa 1970s-1980s; (1 ¾ U-Matic tape) (Box 190, Folder 5)
    - Warhol, Andy - MX Museum Program Broadcast, 1996; (1 VHS tape; in Japanese) (Box 190, Folder 6)
    - [Weiner, Lawrence] - "A First Quarter I and II,", circa 1980s-1990s; (2 VHS tapes) (Box 190, Folder 7)
    - "What's Up in New York" - Featuring Interview with Leo Castelli During "Jasper Johns 35 Years" Exhibition, 1993, January 23; (1 VHS tape) (Box 190, Folder 8)
    - Zoom, 1997, December 7; (2 VHS tapes) (Box 190, Folder 9)